The SCOAN prayer line - the arena of liberty,
where Prophet T.B. Joshua is being used as an instrument of healing, deliverance
and all of God's blessings.
People from different countries all over the globe fall under the power of the Holy Spirit
and freedom comes to every area of their life, in the name of Jesus Christ.
As he prayed for the people, he encountered this lady
and the evil spirit that controlled her life and actions was exposed.
Who are you?
Stand right!
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
I am from the water.
She doesn’t belong to anybody.
She is precious to the kingdom.
You have the spirit of woman.
My master sent me to her to destroy her.
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
I couldn't kill her because I love her.
Deliverance In Jesus’ Name
I'm a spirit woman.
She belongs to me.
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
I made her to love women only.
She is precious and I love her; she is not going to go.
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
I am her wife.
Deliverance In Jesus’ Name
Where the light of God is, darkness has no hiding place.
The evil spirit confessed all its destructive acts in the life of this woman,
and it is finally loosed from her, in the name of Jesus Christ.
To God be the glory - she is free, and she rises to her feet; a new creation in Christ Jesus.
Hallelujah!
TESTIMONY CONTINUES
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Genevieve Anyama, I’m from Imo State; I'm a Nigerian.
I studied in India and the person beside me is my sister.
We both reside in India.
I had the spirit of woman as the prophet had said which was true.
When I was a child, at the age of nine, I had a dream where I found myself in the water
and they crowned me as a king and presented a woman to me to marry as my queen.
When I woke up, I wondered what was going on because I could not understand the dream.
At that age, I just ignored it.
After some time, I changed and abandoned all the male friends that I had.
I didn’t like them anymore and started having more female friends.
I felt so comfortable with them.
I didn’t desire men because I felt like I was already a man; so, why would I have male friends?
That was how that spirit entered into me and started manifesting in me
and I started having that feeling – feelings for my fellow girls.
Can you tell us once again; what was the spirit that was in you then?
I had the spirit of woman.
How did this spirit of woman affect you, and what did it push you to do?
The feeling was getting stronger
and it pushed me to the extent that I became more attracted to them.
I was kind of scared and I was going along with that.
The thing was affecting me so badly that I didn't know myself totally,
and didn’t know what was happening to me.
I saw myself as a man but when I looked into the mirror, I was a girl.
I thought to myself what is happening to me because I am a lady, a girl,
but I behaved like a man.
I wore boys’ clothes and behaved like a boy.
That was how I grew up.
My education was nothing to write home about because my grades were so poor.
I was not concentrating and my health was down as well.
It affected my health, education and way of living.
When I was in India, I went to a private university where I studied nursing.
When I was in India, the feeling was so strong that it affected my subjects
and I could not concentrate on my course anymore.
Through the internet, I felt free to communicate with fellow girls like me who had that same spirit.
How did you get them on the internet - can you explain to us?
It was my hobby.
I liked browsing and searching different sites.
When it came to dating, I only focused on females.
It was a chatting app or sites for lesbians.
That was where I logged in and I could chat freely with those people.
I registered and started communicating there.
I didn’t communicate through my campus or school.
Can you tell us how far you went in your association with these friends you found on internet?
Through the site, I met people who lived near me in the country where I was staying.
I happened to like one of them and we would go out on dates.
From there, we started enjoying a relationship.
How far did you go in the relationship with this lady you found on the internet?
We went deeper like a normal relationship.
We became intimate and we even shared naked pictures and love messages.
Can you tell us what level you were in school?
It was in my third year.
In which school?
I was in my third year of university, studying nursing.
And you told us earlier that it affected your grades.
Can you just explain further how your grades were affected?
What were your grades at school?
It affected my grades – they were beyond poor.
They were below average.
If I read, I would not understand and I would forget.
I couldn’t focus on my studies and it affected me so much in my grades; I even had carryovers.
It also affected my practicals and everything.
How did you finally get delivered of this evil spirit - the spirit of woman?
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
I thank God for my parents.
My mum really loves God so much.
Whenever she watched Emmanuel TV and prayed along,
she would ask us to pray since we had access to the internet.
We could go to the site and pray along with Emmanuel TV
because our grades and health were poor.
So, we watched Emmanuel TV.
Anytime she asked us to read our Bible and pray, we would just ignore her.
We would agree to do it but ignore her advice and end up not doing it.
It affected her as well, especially her health.
Since I was the first one, I was supposed to control her.
I was living my own life and didn’t care.
So, she met bad friends and lived a wayward life – partying, drinking and all of that.
So, any time your mum called you, your response would give her a hint that something was amiss.
Yeah.
What then happened afterwards?
Whenever she called, I tried to cover up but she would still know being a mother.
She would call to ask if I prayed and read my Bible and I would respond that we had done so.
I would tell my mother that I was taking care of my sister
but she would know that things were not good because our grades were poor.
Each time our results came out, we would inform our parents and they saw that it was not working out
and told us we need to come to Nigeria for summer break
to work things out and come for deliverance and healing.
Whenever she mentioned that we should come down to Nigeria,
we would always make excuses.
She would trick us that we were coming down to Nigeria for a summer vacation.
We did not know that we were coming down here;
we thought we were coming for vacation because it was Lagos
where we would have fun with our family.
When we came here, we did not know that it was the building of The SCOAN.
When we came here, we thought the building was nice, like a place for tourists.
We then remembered that we had seen this place online and on Emmanuel TV.
We realised that this was where our parents wanted us to come.
We didn’t want to come here; we were tricked into coming.
So, at the end of the day you found yourself at the prayer-line section that Sunday.
Tell us what happened.
When I was at the prayer section, I did not believe because I was not a spiritual person.
I thought that it was fun and like a drama but I just accepted it believing I would get what I wanted.
As the man of God was moving to where I was, people were just falling.
I thought, “What is going on. This is more than just fun”.
I did not find it fun anymore because people were falling.
When the man of God came near me, I was feeling uncomfortable and a lot of heat.
I was not feeling my usual self.
I only remembered when the man of God touched me and when I got off the ground.
I stood up from the ground and wondered what had happened.
- And that was how you received your deliverance?
- Yes.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus!
How many of you went to the prayer-line that day?
Me and my sister.
- So, the two of you were delivered that day?
- Yeah.
Hallelujah!
Put your hands together once again for Jesus!
Since that day you received that divine touch, through His anointed one - Prophet T.B. Joshua,
as you were just watching on the screen of your TV...
We can see when she was at the prayer-line section,
and after that touch from the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua,
the evil spirit was manifesting, and at the end of the day she was delivered,
removed from that kingdom of darkness, from the captivity of satan and placed into the kingdom of light.
We give God all the glory.
Tell us the changes you have seen in yourself, since you received your deliverance.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
After my deliverance, I became my normal self again.
When I saw what had happened, I realised that this was the cause of my problem.
God took away the ‘poor and lame’ brain and put a brighter and smarter brain inside of me.
Whenever I read, it is like a magnet, it just stays there.
My grades were picking up and I was not even reading much.
Before, I needed to read for about four hours and about seven text books but now, I hardly read.
God has given me guidance on how to read.
We heard from the sister that before she received that deliverance, she spent hours reading,
but at the end of the day there were low grades.
But immediately after she received that deliverance, she now has a "magnetic" brain.
Anything she reads just gets stuck there and her grades improved radically.
That is indeed a radical transformation.
Let us put our hands together for Jesus!
What about your social life - the feeling you used to have towards women like yourself?
How is that, now that you have received your deliverance?
After my deliverance, I went back and those friends I had before were avoiding me.
Who? Mention those friends.
Those friends that had the same spirit of woman.
I think they saw something in me because even if I greeted them, it was as if I was an outcast.
I was thinking of how I was going to tell them one by one
that I was not going to associate with them anymore but God just helped me with that.
It was as if He put a mask on me that they could not recognise me.
That was how I saw myself because they would just find their way out.
Hallelujah!
That really proves that you have been taken out of this kingdom of darkness.
That evil spirit that was in you, that linked you with others having the same spirit, has been removed.
You can see that you are now a changed person.
God always gives us that evidence, proof to believe in Him.
We give God all the glory for your deliverance.
Before we go on to listen to your sister, we just want you to explain one or two things,
because we can see a board next to you.
You said that before your deliverance you had like a dull brain.
Your grades were so poor and you didn't have any hope of graduating from the university.
But after your deliverance you told us what God has done with regard to your education.
Explain to us what we are seeing on the board next to you.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
I don't know how to explain this because I'm so happy.
I thought that when I came out of school, I would come out with just a pass.
I thought I would fail or just pass.
I thank God of Prophet T.B. Joshua whom He used to deliver me from the hands of the devil.
I came out with a First Class Bachelor of Science in Nursing (Honours).
Hallelujah! Shall we put our hands together for Jesus!
Put your hands together beautifully for Jesus Christ.
We see that you came out with First Class Honours in nursing - that is really wonderful.
This is somebody that was having very low grades.
Her grades were so poor because of the evil spirit that affected every area of her life.
It is a proof that when Jesus delivers you, He delivers you completely, effectually
and every area of your life will be transformed.
You can see the proof of this in the life of the sister.
She has shown us the results of her studies in India;
she came out with first class honours in nursing.
Hallelujah!
What are the other documents we are seeing next to it?
The next one is my license to practise as a registered Nurse and Midwife.
Hallelujah! We give God all the glory.
You have said it all, and we give God all the glory for this wonderful thing that He has done in your life.
Before we go on to hear your own advice, we would like to listen to your sister,
whom we know that God Almighty has also transformed radically.
Please tell us your name and your testimony.
Good Morning everybody!
Good Morning, children of God!
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Henrietta Anyama.
The person standing beside me is my elder sister.
Don’t get confused about the size.
She has said it all.
She is not the type that talks.
I am the mouth organ in the house.
Let me perform my own part.
My life before I received salvation was totally something I would not like to think about
or want to go back to for any reason.
Our lives in India -
and even before we travelled – we hardly went to church.
Despite my mother being a prayer warrior and my father being grounded in the things of God,
there was no push or morale to talk about God or anything related to church.
I didn’t go to church or read my Bible; I didn’t even have a Bible.
It was back in 2014 when I came to The SCOAN that I got my first Bible
and my mum bought it for me.
My life in school was a wayward life.
I smoked, drank anything and hang out with girls, not the ones that would tell me about God.
This problem really affected me but academically when you have the grace of God,
God would always be giving you signs to come back to Him.
Academically, God was always there for me.
My wayward life was really affecting me, giving me depression – I could not concentrate.
I knew that if I had died, I would not even be a step from that road that would take me to Heaven.
After the deliverance, I know I am a better person and I can take two more steps
and I would be on my way to Heaven.
It is a continuous one; it has not ended.
My sister could not control me because she was doing her own and I was doing my own.
Everybody was on their own.
If our mum called us, she would say that the man of God was praying.
I would ask, “Which man of God?”
She would reply, “Prophet T.B. Joshua”.
I would say, “We don’t hear about him here”.
She replied that it was Emmanuel TV and that we should log onto the internet.
I told her that we did not have a subscription for the internet.
When the Prophet would be praying for the viewers,
that is the time she would call us and put it on loud speaker.
We would be like, “Amen. Yes, Lord! Amen”.
When she ended the call, my sister would be wondering what was wrong with our mother.
Can you tell us what finally pulled you out of that, and today you are a living testimony?
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
I thank God for my mother so much.
I thank God that she was the one who gave birth to me.
It happened in 2014, when she asked us to come home.
Holiday time is the time you have fun.
How can you come to Nigeria and be caged and you don’t have freedom?
In 2014, she asked us to come home and it was like she was dragging us back to Nigeria.
What do you mean by being caged here in Nigeria?
You mean that your parents... - explain what you meant by that.
Being caged means you don’t have freedom of your own.
When you are at home, you have to be a good girl.
You can’t have bad friends or go out.
If it is 5pm at my place, you are not going anywhere.
My father will say, you are a girl and you have to stay at home.
You can’t have friends that you would go and drink with.
Where would you go and drink when everybody knows you are the daughter of this person?
You would be caged but over there, nobody knows your identity,
so you are free to do whatever thing you want to do.
I was free to do whatever thing I wanted to do.
Coming home to Nigeria was going to cut off that freedom – that was the cage I meant.
My mother asked us to come home and we came home.
We heard about Lagos and how there is a beach and cool places where you can hang out.
My mother said that we were coming to Lagos.
She even made sure that the flight would land in Lagos.
I prepared my dressing for adventure – the way I was dressed that day!
When we got here, the environment was cool, like a foreign place.
I was like, yes, they are stepping up the game.
The next thing, I saw one picture that looked like something I had seen on Emmanuel TV.
I said, “This woman, so she has brought me here”.
I said that I would comply.
We were here and we were lucky we got on the prayer line and every miracle started from there.
The miracle happened when the man of God prayed for me
and it took three people to help me stand up because I had gained weight.
I stood up and that was the only thing I noticed.
There was no pain but I felt I was being lifted from the ground.
I felt lighter, more cool and differently immediately.
I started seeing things from a different perspective, other than what I used to see before.
Shall we put our hands together for Jesus!
Tell us other changes you have seen, since you received your deliverance.
As I am now, just one shot of vodka and I would want to sleep.
It would be like a sleeping tablet for the next 24 hours.
Before, no matter what they mixed, I would drink and still stand.
Now, if I just taste it, I would become tipsy.
That was a sign that the brain that was used to drinking was no longer there,
that brain had come out and a different brain is in my head.
After our deliverance, we went back to school because we were in our third year.
We went back to complete our final year.
Everything was different, our friends -
those girls who clubbed, none of them came close to me again.
It was as if something had happened to me, as if I had another face.
Even when I talked to them, they would give me attitude.
I said to myself, “Let them go; they are the ones who will lose not me”.
Regarding our grades at school – our exam time was getting close and before,
when the exam got close, we would want to be very close to our books and read
but when the exam got close after my deliverance,
I wasn’t even getting close to my books because I believed that God had done it already.
I did not put in so much human effort as before.
I am a brand new Ebere.
What about this life you used to live on campus
because you said you went back to the same school after your deliverance?
Can you tell us; when you found yourself in that same school -
how were you able to disassociate yourself from those bad friends you were involved with before?
When I got back there, they all went away.
They weren’t coming close to me anymore.
When you take out a space in your life, you have to fill it with another thing.
I wasn’t going to church.
The things of God did not interest me so much.
I joined a living church and became a part of the choir there.
When I sang hymns, people would be crying.
Watch the screen of your TV.
On the left-hand side, we can see when she was being delivered,
couple of years ago, when she came to the prayer line-section.
We can see the evil spirit in her manifesting.
That was when the evil spirit was cast out and you can see her right on the floor.
The evil spirit was totally cast out and that was how she became a changed person.
We give glory to God Almighty!
Having watched this clip, we want to ask you;
you said that academically, spiritually, even your social life was totally transformed...
Can you tell us in what other way did God Almighty bless you,
before you travelled back to India to complete your studies?
Number one, I had the opportunity to get delivered.
Number two, I had the grace to get the Morning Water and the Morning Sticker
that is anointed by God through Prophet T.B. Joshua.
What we did not expect happened, the man of God supported us financially.
The fresh foundation that he laid
was what brought about the good result you are seeing there.
It was not me but God.
All throughout the exams, as we were writing, all of us believed that we were going to make it
because they saw the enthusiasm in me.
Each time we submitted the paper, I would spray the Morning Water on them.
We were only allowed to go in with a pen and paper but my Morning Water was always here.
When I brought it out, they asked why I was having it.
I replied that it was my Morning Water that I used for prayer.
I took it and sprayed it on each paper, from day one to the last day of the exams.
I sprayed every paper as we were submitting them.
Praise God!
Hallelujah!
And how was your grade, after you wrote your final exam,
according to what we are seeing on the board next to you?
I was not expecting anything less than First Class because I knew God was with me.
God did it. He perfected everything.
Hallelujah!
Let us put our hands together for Jesus!
Put your hands together for Jesus Christ!
Can you just explain the documents to us?
After everything, the results came out and I got Pass-1 Division.
Now, I have a BSc Honours in Nursing – a registered Nurse and Midwife
at the Nursing Council in New Delhi, India.
Thank God!
This was our graduation picture.
This picture was taken at the final practical we had.
This is me - very happy because I knew God did it.
This is my sister.
This is me and my sister on the day of graduation.
This was our first delivery in the practical exams.
You have seen a lot of proofs of what God has done in the life of these two sisters.
We give God all the glory.
As a youth, listen to your parents because they will never deceive you.
They mean well for you.
Let us hear a word of advice from your sister.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My advice is for you to stick to God.
As a youth, this is the time for you to come close to God.
Hallelujah!
We have heard a wonderful advice from the two sisters.
We just want to advise you as well. Now that God Almighty has set you free,
taken you out of the kingdom of darkness and placed you in the kingdom of light,
all this you have received is for the salvation of your soul.
Make God's Word the standard for your life,
meaning that no state of being is as rewarding as living in tune with God.
Holy are you Lord
All creation calls you Lord
Worthy is Your name
We worship Your majesty
Awesome God
You are my Father
You alone
Mighty are Your miracles
Just live in me
Stay in me
Hallelujah!
Put your hands together for Jesus!
Put your hands together beautifully for the miracle-working God.
We give God all the glory.
Once again, as you have been delivered and set free from that kingdom of darkness,
make sure you follow Jesus along the way.
We pray that God will give you that enablement and grace to continue to follow Him along the way,
so that the blessings, the deliverance you have received will remain permanent, in Jesus' name!
Hallelujah! Put your hands together once again for Jesus!
TT ROBERT BEGIER 02/10/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 03/11/2018